const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"A 50-year-old man presents to the emergency department with worsening dyspnea and confusion. As his symptoms progress, he becomes obtunded and experiences respiratory distress, requiring intubation. A central line is inserted for medical management. Which anatomical structure, derived embryologically from the right common cardinal vein, is accessed by the central line placement?","answers":[{"option":"Jugular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior vena cava","bool":false},{"option":"Common carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Internal carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superior vena cava","bool":true}]},{"id":1,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"During adolescence, which type of intelligence peaks and decreases with age without relying on prior knowledge?","answers":[{"option":"Crystallized","bool":false},{"option":"Practical","bool":false},{"option":"Analytical","bool":false},{"option":"Emotional","bool":false},{"option":"Fluid","bool":true}]},{"id":2,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"What is the net filtration pressure across the capillary bed if capillary hydrostatic pressure is 15 mmHg, capillary colloid osmotic pressure is 20 mmHg, interstitial fluid hydrostatic pressure is 5 mmHg, and interstitial fluid colloid osmotic pressure is 10mm Hg?","answers":[{"option":"15 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"5 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"0 mmHg","bool":true},{"option":"10 mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"20 mmHg","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"What percentage of the blood pumped by the heart is sent to the lungs through the pulmonary artery for the purpose of oxygenation?","answers":[{"option":"25%","bool":false},{"option":"50%","bool":false},{"option":"12%","bool":false},{"option":"100%","bool":true},{"option":"1%","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"In radiology, what structures form the cardiac silhouette on the right side?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary trunk","bool":false},{"option":"Right ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Tricuspid valve","bool":false},{"option":"Right atrium","bool":true}]},{"id":5,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"What is the primary role of HDL?","answers":[{"option":"Remove cholesterol from peripheral tissues","bool":true},{"option":"Carry cholesterol from liver to the peripheral tissues","bool":false},{"option":"Oxidation of LDL cholesterol","bool":false},{"option":"Blood clot formation","bool":false},{"option":"Has inflammatory effects","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"Which of the following blood vessels has the highest amount of elastic tissue?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Medium size arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Aorta","bool":true},{"option":"Muscular artery","bool":false},{"option":"Arterioles","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"A 12-year-old male child experienced temporary occlusion in the artery of his middle finger which resolved on its own. What could explain this phenomenon?","answers":[{"option":"Reactive hyperemia","bool":true},{"option":"Ischemia","bool":false},{"option":"Active hyperemia","bool":false},{"option":"Artery occlusion","bool":false},{"option":"Collateral vessel damage","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"A 62-year-old male with heart disease presents to the OPD with an O2 consumption rate of 200ml/min, with 0.20ml/min at the peripheral arterial end and 0.15ml/min at the venous end. What is the cardiac output?","answers":[{"option":"4 L/min","bool":true},{"option":"25 L/min","bool":false},{"option":"10 L/min","bool":false},{"option":"2.5 L/min","bool":false},{"option":"1.0 L/min","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"A company owner is working to manage diabetes among their employees. Which of the following factors could be modified to prevent diabetes?","answers":[{"option":"Ethnicity","bool":false},{"option":"Gender","bool":false},{"option":"Obesity","bool":true},{"option":"Age","bool":false},{"option":"Race","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"What could be the reason for the physiological splitting of S2?","answers":[{"option":"Delayed aortic valve closure","bool":false},{"option":"Tricuspid valve closure","bool":false},{"option":"Delayed pulmonary valve closure","bool":true},{"option":"Mitral valve closure","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary valve opening","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"From which structure does the right coronary artery originate?","answers":[{"option":"Right posterior aortic sinus","bool":true},{"option":"Pulmonary trunk","bool":false},{"option":"Left posterior aortic sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior aortic sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Left ventricles","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"What condition leads to the formation of tall T waves on an ECG?","answers":[{"option":"Hypernatremia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypocalcemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypercalcemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperkalemia","bool":true},{"option":"Hypokalemia","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"Which structure is absorbed into the right atrium to form the sinus venarum?","answers":[{"option":"Aortic sac","bool":false},{"option":"Left horn","bool":false},{"option":"Superior vena cava","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary veins","bool":false},{"option":"Right horn","bool":true}]},{"id":14,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"What are the potential side effects of nitroglycerin?","answers":[{"option":"Seizures","bool":false},{"option":"Throbbing headache","bool":true},{"option":"Anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Edema","bool":false},{"option":"Constipation","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"What is the recommended antiplatelet medication for treating acute myocardial infarction?","answers":[{"option":"Clopidogrel","bool":false},{"option":"Heparin","bool":false},{"option":"Warfarin","bool":false},{"option":"Enoxaparin","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":true}]},{"id":16,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"Which of the following drugs causes the closure of L-type calcium channel?","answers":[{"option":"Esmolol","bool":false},{"option":"Metoprolol","bool":false},{"option":"Amiodarone","bool":false},{"option":"Furosemide","bool":false},{"option":"Diltiazem","bool":true}]},{"id":17,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"Which of the following enzymes are responsible for joining 2 acetyl-CoA in ketogenesis?","answers":[{"option":"HMG CoA synthase","bool":false},{"option":"Acetyl CoA dehydrogenase","bool":false},{"option":"Carboxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Carnitine","bool":false},{"option":"Thiolase","bool":true}]},{"id":18,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"Which class of drugs reduces LDL cholesterol?","answers":[{"option":"Calcium channel blockers","bool":false},{"option":"Beta blockers","bool":false},{"option":"Statins","bool":true},{"option":"Diuretics","bool":false},{"option":"ACE inhibitors","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"Which of the following findings is associated with Cushing syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Gigantism","bool":false},{"option":"Reduced weight","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglycemia","bool":false},{"option":"Increased muscle mass","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":true}]},{"id":20,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"What is the name of the structure that connects the atria to the ventricles in the conducting system?","answers":[{"option":"Sinoatrial node","bool":false},{"option":"Atrioventricular node","bool":true},{"option":"Purkinje fiber","bool":false},{"option":"Interventricular septum","bool":false},{"option":"Bundle of His","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"Which vessel experiences the highest level of tension?","answers":[{"option":"Arteries","bool":true},{"option":"Veins","bool":false},{"option":"Capillaries","bool":false},{"option":"Venules","bool":false},{"option":"Arterioles","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"What causes the C wave in the atrial pressure curve?","answers":[{"option":"Closure of tricuspid valve","bool":false},{"option":"Opening of pulmonary valve","bool":false},{"option":"Bulging of tricuspid valve in right atrium","bool":true},{"option":"Opening of tricuspid valve","bool":false},{"option":"Closure of aortic valve","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"An HIV patient asks to keep his disease confidential. Which of the following principles of medical ethics is this?","answers":[{"option":"Beneficence","bool":false},{"option":"Confidentiality","bool":true},{"option":"Autonomy","bool":false},{"option":"Equity","bool":false},{"option":"Non-maleficence","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"What is the embryonic structure that forms the smooth area of the right atrium?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary trunk","bool":false},{"option":"Sinus venarum","bool":true},{"option":"Truncus arteriosus","bool":false},{"option":"Trabeculae carneae","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen ovale","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"Which of the following features are common to both pulmonary and systemic circulation?","answers":[{"option":"Compliance","bool":false},{"option":"Resistance","bool":false},{"option":"Pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Flow","bool":true},{"option":"Conductance","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"What is the phase of the cardiac cycle responsible for the sound heard after S2 at the left border?","answers":[{"option":"Isovolumetric relaxation","bool":true},{"option":"Rapid ventricular filling","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial contraction","bool":false},{"option":"Rapid ejection","bool":false},{"option":"Isovolumetric contraction","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"What is the sponge-like structure found in the ventricle of the heart?","answers":[{"option":"Fossa ovalis","bool":false},{"option":"Trabeculae carneae","bool":true},{"option":"Musculi pectinati","bool":false},{"option":"Sulcus chrysalis","bool":false},{"option":"Sulcus terminalis","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"1st-year/cardiovascular/2023","question":"When performing a clinical examination, if the middle part of the esophagus is compressed, which part of the heart is most likely causing this compression?","answers":[{"option":"Left ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Left atrium","bool":true},{"option":"Right ventricle","bool":false},{"option":"Aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Right atrium","bool":false}]}]
export default arr